Selfishly, it's to our benefit to pay
you a little bit of extra time to put
some of that extra work into your report
so that we can more quickly
understand the impact, reproduce, get
you a reward faster.
>> Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical think, right?
Yeah, dude.
>> Sup, Packers? We've got an exciting
announcement. Threat Locker Zero Trust
World Conference is back in 2026. It's
going to be March 4th to March 6 in
Orlando, Florida. It's freaking gorgeous
down there, too, during that time. And
yours truly is going to be there. I'm
going to be there on Wednesday, March
4th. I'm going to be leading a hands-on
hacking workshop. I'll be one of many.
So, there's lots of fun hacking
workshops you can get involved in. Um,
and it's going to be a great time.
There's tons of sessions, workshops,
other people there to network with. It's
going to be a great conference. So, if
you're local to Orlando or if you're up
for the travel, um, this is a great way
for you to use that employer uh,
training budget that you've got. Also,
um, for critical thinking listeners,
there's a discount of $200 off. You can
use the code ZTW, right, for zero trust
world. CTB26.
ZTWCTBB26
when you register. That'll be on the
screen and in the description as well.
It's going to be a great time. I hope to
see you guys there. All right, let's go
back to the show.
What's up, hackers? It's Brandon Gret
here uh here for this week in Bug Bounty
and we have two articles from Hacker One
and some exciting news about Nong Go for
you. So, let's jump in.
First up, we have an article with none
other than our very own Reszo and Hacker
on with Luke Stevens aka Hack Luke. And
this is AI red teaming explained by AI
red teamers. Now, when I saw this on
Twitter, it did make me laugh a little
bit as I was thinking the same but never
actually thought to comment about it.
But the term AI red teaming has been
thrown around so many times I have lost
count. whether you're on Twitter, in
research articles, whatever it could be.
And this article aims to clear up some
of the ambiguity around the term. So,
Hackloop posted a poll on X. And the
results probably left people more
confused than it did give anyone answers
if you did see these polls at the time.
Now, people ask, when you hear AI red
teaming, what do you think? um 43%
jailbreaking, testing an LLM, testing an
app that uses AI, or actually red
teaming with an autonomous AI hackbot.
As you can see, the results are pretty
varied. Luckily, very luckily, we have
an expert on the pod, Reszo, to go
through and actually clear this up a
little bit. and his comment on this
thread made me laugh so much at the
time, but to clear it up, AI red teaming
is actually when you are attacking a
real world application that uses and
implements AI features. So imagine
you're on a target that has some AI
functionality, whether it's a enhanced
crawler, a chatbot, an agent, any sort
of AI powered workflow. Once you start
attacking that and testing it, that is
the simple definition of AI red. Oh, and
here we go. The actual simple
definition, AI red teaming is the
practice of attacking systems and
applications that include AI components
in order to identify real security
weaknesses.
Now hopefully that clears it up because
I've been in many conversations as of
late when some people think AI red
teaming is you are on a red team
operation which is AI enhance with
tooling. other people. Well, I mean, the
poll spoke for itself, but it's pretty
much spread all over the place. But
luckily, Hakuan brow this article to
clear that up. Now, if you are a hunter
and you're looking for some additional
scope like I've been doing lately, have
a look at some of these bigger targets
which are implementing AI slowly into
their ecosystems. It's a very good it's
a very rich attack surface and I
recommend doing it for some AI red
teaming.
Now the next one this is perfect if you
do plan to do some AI research and that
is the hacker one good faith security
research initiative which we've all been
protected by for a very long time since
2022. the gold standard safe harbor it's
called has now been extended to cover AI
now you might be thinking weren't we
already covered by that in the original
one and the short answer I think legally
no there's a lot of ambiguity around AI
research and AI safety but now luckily
there is a framework out which covers
this and makes sure that we are safe if
we do decide to do some security
research um on AI so they have linked
their standards as well about what this
covers and how you're protected. I won't
go into it entirely, but the good news
is now as of 2026,
we are covered if you do want to do some
good faith and that is the key here.
Good faith security research on AI. So
definitely check it out if that is your
jam, if you're thinking of doing some AI
research yourself. Um, but we're
covered. Now finally
we have got
a Nulcon exclusive
uh live hacking event with Adobe. Now
Ncon is in Goa from 28th of Feb to the
1st of March. So quite a big conference.
Now Adobe are going to be here doing an
exclusive live hacking event. If any of
the listeners will be there definitely
consider it. Check it out. There's some
pretty cool prizes to be won. There's
not much information on the site about
it yet, so you're going to have to check
it out in person. Um, they've told us
there's going to be some very, very nice
prizes for the top three AI related
vulnerabilities.
Now, I'm not sure what they are as of
yet, but if they say it's going to be
good, I have no doubt it will be. So,
definitely check that out. Now, that's
it for this week in Bug Bounty. We now
have a very cool episode coming up with
Google. Enjoy.
>> All right, guys. Today we've got the
Google Cloud VRP team with us. We've got
Darby Hopkins and Michael Cotay or just
normally Cotay, right?
>> Cot.
>> That's it. That's it. Um, and the goal
of today's episode is to teach you guys
how to optimize your your money that you
that you make when hacking on Google
Cloud VRP. There's there's some nuances
to the Google system that are not there
in other parts of the Bug Bounty world.
So, we're going to kind of explain how
to succeed in hacking on GCP. We're
going to run through some um you know,
scenarios and how they align with their
table. Um and we're going to get some
insights from the crazy live hacking
events you guys have had uh over the
past what only like year and a half of
running the program, right?
>> Yeah, we launched in internally in July
of 2024 and externally at the and I
think you might have been there at in
Malaga in October of 2024. So, that's
kind of when we went fully live.
>> That's crazy, man. I'm I'm so sad I
missed that event. I didn't get to
participate in that one. I had a family
vacation scheduled, but I've heard it
was legendary.
>> Very fun. Malaga is beautiful.
>> Yeah. Um All right. Well, let's jump
right into it. Um you guys recently had
a crazy live hacking event with, you
know, $1.6 million in rewards, 160 plus
reports submitted. Um that's an amazing
accomplishment. Can you guys tell us a
little bit about how that event went and
uh how we as hackers can can uh you know
get at some of those I assume you know
must have been systemic issues that were
ranging you know in GCP.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. I can talk a little bit
about kind of what happened on the back
end that that event. So that that was
one of our um bug spot events. So
Google, our various VRPs do bug swats
throughout the year. That one was
specifically focused on cloud and we had
five or six products in our scope. So
first cloud focused bug swat since we
launched in October 24 and that happened
in June of 25 out in Sunnyale,
California. And let me tell you, it was
it was explosive for us internally. I
think
>> I imagine
>> we launched we we opened up the
submission window like three or four
weeks before the live hack hacking
event.
>> Woke up that morning immediately 25
bucks in the queue.
>> Oh my god.
>> Which is
>> big for us. That's a lot. Um just from
like a small set of researchers.
>> And then it only grew from there and
throughout the month. I mean, our
submission window was only open for four
or five weeks and we got 160 reports
just in the scope of that bug swat, not
to mention all of the other reports we
were receiving as part of our normal
submission.
>> It was crazy.
>> That's crazy. Yeah. I will say, you
know, four weeks, four weeks is a while
for these live hacking events. You know,
a lot of times what we see is, you know,
two weeks, two weeks and some change,
sometimes even as little as 10 days. um
you know, so I'm sure that contributed
to it, but like either way, you you you
cut it. You know, 160 reports and 1.6
million rewarded is a crazy life hacking
event. Um and I was I was I was drooling
on the outside of that. I was like, "Oh,
I got to I got to get in on that next
time." Um so could you tell us a little
bit about what happened there? Because
like as a hacker on the outside, I want
to think, you know, I want to look at
that and I'm saying, okay, look, some
some hackers, they really understood the
threat model. They found, you know,
something that, you know, might be
applied in multiple, you know, different
areas throughout your scope and they
just boom, you know, pounded it into the
ground, right, is how you kind of get
that many reports through. Um, so can
you lift the veil for us a little bit on
what kind of reports you were seeing?
Um, what kind of impact these people
were going for, that sort of thing?
>> Yeah, one of the really interesting
pieces about this one was again, so
you're right, like normally it's like a
week before, two weeks before we open
the submission window, it ends uh at the
end. But this one, we're like, all
right, let's open it wider. But we also
uh for the first time we had two
enterprise level
uh products that typically don't see any
researcher reports because they're so
expensive uh to hack on.
>> So exclusive scope as well here. Okay.
>> Yeah. Like we did so it was basically
not seen by researchers before
a little sense. And so I think they we
heard beforehand that they were drooling
at the opportunity cuz we got them
credentials. So there were a shockingly
among those there was some were dupes uh
but there were a lot of we saw rce we
saw privilege escalations we saw uh
really interesting like these run as
viewer attacks within some of our
products um
>> where very very interesting way more
unique reports than I would have
expected
>> that's awesome so okay so I'm hearing
some privilege escalation I'm hearing
some like you know actual server inside
rce on some integrations. The run as
thing is really interesting and of
course fascinating for any
>> very interesting
>> hacker to look at.
>> Um Darby, did you have any comments on
that as well?
>> Yeah, more specifically on um privilege
escalation. We saw a few reports
um exploiting service account
impersonation. This is kind of a common
thing that we see on cloud VRP.
>> Let me write that down.
com thing on Google Cloud VRP, I'm sure
common thing on AWS and Azure as well.
This is just kind of how cloud works.
But
>> for this particular bug swat, a few of
our top reports
>> um exploited those types of issues
>> very deliberately and very successfully
like highly privileged default service
accounts.
>> Very nice. Okay. taking advantage of
>> one was especially interesting uh and
we'll probably provide a link to he's
actually publishing it uh today or
tomorrow.
>> Oh, heck yeah.
>> It'll go out with this episode. Awesome.
>> Yeah. Uh he
he found something that we hadn't been
able to prove like we thought it was and
there were like so many similar reports
that we were basically going to say like
oh you can impersonate this but so what?
Like it basically you're there's no
increase in like what you can actually
achieve from it. But he showed like, oh,
from this you can actually achieve like
impersonate another serv account, which
is like much higher privileged, which
got actually like like 10 people uh 10
researchers were awarded at the event.
So he was very popular,
>> dude. Yeah, dude. That's amazing. That's
Oh, I'm sure. Oh, so other people
submitted reports. They were missing a
little bit of their of their, you know,
chain. This guy completed it and
everybody got rewarded.
>> Yes. And we weren't able to either like
we knew something was there but we
couldn't we we had no way to and he
found just the the one that you could
impersonate that guy to everyone.
>> Oh man, shout out to this legendary guy.
We're going to put it in the description
as legendary guy. Uh you know when he
publishes that write up. That's amazing.
Um all right.
>> Can we mention his name?
>> I mean he's his name is up on our blog
about this event. We can probably call
him out.
>> Do it. Who is it?
>> Yeah. Jacob Damaraki. Ah, Jacob, of
course. Okay.
>> Yeah, JD. He's um
>> I think he won our most creative
slashsurprising report reward.
>> Awesome.
>> For that bug spot event,
>> Jacob, shout out to you, man. I I as a
as a hacker, I so appreciate just people
that complete the chain, you know, and
other and also I think that speaks to
Yell's program as well where you're
like, okay, this guy completed it, you
know, and these other people that have
parts of the chain, you know, present or
maybe even in different areas that also
works for them, so we're going to we're
going to make sure they get paid. Um,
>> we try and like and honestly like we
tell people this and sometimes I don't
know that they believe it, but we do pay
out the max impact that we can prove. In
this case like while we looked we
couldn't find anything once he was able
to show it like everyone got rewarded
based on now this new and they all had
unique starting points so which allowed
us to then go back and say oh you
couldn't you even though like the
singular mitigation like by not allowing
them to impersonate anymore but yeah
very
>> that's amazing that's that's really good
and I I I love that you know and I have
seen that time and time again with
Google employees coming through looking
at my bug applying their knowledge of
the product, you know, and and
understanding the full impact there,
which I think is is great. And and
that's even better, you know, when we're
at these live hacking events because you
guys bring the product team out there
sometimes, right? So, we're sitting
there with the people that wrote the
code and we're like this, you know, that
and then they're like, "Oh, yeah, you
shouldn't have access to that." you know
um and they really understand depthy
um you know what what the impact is and
they can explain it to us which helps us
download so much easier because one of
the main challenges for hackers
especially in a complex environment like
GCP is fully understanding the product
the threat model the intricacies of
everything and if you've got a product
engineer with you there it's so much
better
>> yeah I'll second that I mean Cotay and I
work for Google we are cloud security
engineers and it's even hard for us
sometimes
We have a few hundred products in our
scope. Um, and we rely on our product
teams a lot. Um,
>> yeah,
>> I mean pretty much
every single bug uh that comes through
that we validate, you know, we do our
initial triage, reproduction, make sure
like there's actually something here, it
then gets filed with our product teams
and they will kind of look at it, agree
like yes, this is this is a valid issue.
We can employ a fix here. Um, so we we
rely on their product expertise a lot
>> and we kind of collaborate on rewards
oftentimes.
>> That's great. I I do have some questions
about that because in prepping for this
episode, guys, you know, I did a call
with them and we were talking about it
and they gave me permission to quote
unquote grill them on the workings of
uh, you know, GCP VRP and I have some I
have some questions that I'm excited to
hear you answer. Um and but I think
overall you know the the posture is you
guys I mean you guys are a relatively
young program obviously experiencing
wild success. Um, and I think one of the
things that has contributed to that is
your your willingness to grow and to
listen to feedback from the hackers and
and actually even um, you know, after
this live hacking event, right, that you
guys had, you released a lot of changes
to your to your VRP policy page and and
bounties to make things more
understandable and helpful for the
hacker. Um, so I think that's that's a
great step in the right direction. I was
wondering if you could give me a quick
summary of like what the changes I think
it was in September of last year maybe.
um were and and how those clarify um
your threat model for hackers.
>> One before that though I do want to say
while we are young
>> thankfully and like everyone is familiar
with the Google VRPA it's not like we
started from scratch so I they I I won't
call them up by name but like the Google
VRP is excellent at what they do.
They're like really well embedded in the
community. So like they were a huge
stepping stone to like quickly hitting
the ground running.
>> Yeah. Yeah, and they're the OGs, you
know, they've been around for forever. I
mean, a Google VRP has. So, a lot of
good experience passed along there.
>> You want to go into some of the the
reward changes?
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah, that's uh that's my
passion. Um I uh yeah, we we started off
with kind of a a rewards table. Speaking
of the Google VRP that was heavily based
on their um triedand-true model for you
know this is core Google products like
workspace that uh fit under the Google
VRP. So when the cloud VRP kind of split
out our rewards table still looked a lot
like theirs. I mean a little bit more
honed in on kind of the the cloud attack
service. But as time went on, right, it
had been roughly a year since we'd been
operating since our internal launch in
July of 24,
about a year when we had our bug swat
event in June. And it kind of just we
were spending a lot of time in our
rewards panel discussing
some of these even lower severity bugs.
Um, like I think we had an S1A
category previously that was really
broadly written and almost every time we
would have an S1 bug, which by the way
there's that's like most of them.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, we're like, huh, I wonder which
category it fits into. Well, it the
based on the language it's S1A, but then
it doesn't really feel that high impact,
right? And we were spending so much time
discussing just where to fit the bugs
into our rewards table, right? We we
want to be fair. We want the researchers
to understand as best they can why we
rate things the way that we do. We want
to be transparent.
So
along with the time that we were
spending in panel which was just not
really effective and also to help
researchers kind of understand where
we're coming from increase transparency
we kicked off a pretty big initiative to
update that table.
>> S1A was the worst if we couldn't
understand like and debated incessantly
about it. How are our researchers ever
going to understand S1A versus S1B?
>> Yeah. And and and it also as a
researcher, you know, one I have a bunch
of questions about that I'd like to
pepper you with before we we move along,
you know, explaining the Google system
of S, S0, S1, S2, you know, um uh and
and also the other, you know, ratings
that you guys have. But totally, you
know, when you have a broadly worded
category there and and it's also a
little bit higher up in the table, you
know, that is like our [__] as hackers.
we're like, "Yes, that's where I'm
going." You know, I'mma find one of
those, you know, and then and then, you
know, you find something that you think
matches that category,
>> but then, you know, it's like, "Ah,
well, the impact isn't really there, but
it matches the category." You know, that
puts us that puts everybody in a bad
situation because you guys are looking
at this and you're like, "Ah, this
doesn't really make sense." And the
researchers disappointed and Yeah. So,
I'm glad to see you guys did some some
reworking there.
>> Yeah, 100%. And we we never want
researchers to feel like, you know, I
mean, I I think that you you experienced
this firsthand, Justin, right? So,
submitting a report. Actually, I watched
one of your previous your recent
episodes
>> and you were talking I think probably
about our our Vegas event, right?
>> Um
>> maybe
>> and how like it it didn't go as expected
and we we had gotten that from
researchers before. this will always be
and forever be a thing with bug bounty.
But that's what we wanted to try and
reduce was that that feeling of
disappointments like hey maybe you don't
understand the impact of this or I was
expecting to get 10,000 out of this bug
and I only got five or 3k which still a
lot but not 10. So um we made a lot of
changes to the table to increase
specificity, right? We we wanted to be a
little bit more objective with our
definitions on the rewards table and
make it like very clear like this
clearly within this category
>> while still kind of maintaining the
ability to be a little bit flexible on
our end because especially with cloud um
a lot can change the impact of the issue
like where are the attackers starting
>> totally
>> what data what specifically what type of
data they can access at on the back end
of that exploit can change a lot.
>> Um,
>> absolutely.
>> So,
>> yeah, and and we will we will change it
more. I guarantee.
>> Yeah, that's perfect. You know, that
that helps the growth there. Um, I do
have a couple things I want to swing
back around to with regards to like
having success hacking on Google. Um,
like you know, what kind of quirks there
are to your environment, how how do we
get things set up as a researcher and
really understand the app. But before we
do that, I think it is helpful for the
listeners to understand what we're
talking about when we say, you know, S1,
S0, you know, tier one, you know, P1,
all of these these um, you know, Google
specific in some ways, um,
terminologies. So um can you talk a
little bit about like what S0 S1 means
versus C 0 you know C1 and then also how
explain how your tiering system works in
Google um with the various products that
you have.
>> Yeah. So as zero you can typically think
about it as like unauthenticated. So can
you go in and take data from someone in
which you have like no permissions no
relationship between between the two
accounts S1 you start from like an
authenticated position. So like are less
least severe is like I forget what it is
now. S1F maybe where it's like a single
service like hey you already have
permissions in that service and you can
escalate privileges and that'll be like
our least severe which is like the most
severe would be like S1A where it's like
complete hey you already have
permissions in the project but you can
come go like complete project takeover
>> and S2 is like severity 2 is kind of
like our catch all um like
less least impactful um something needs
to change but not necessarily you're not
excilating data or in the the way that
you might expect.
>> I see. Okay. So S0 we're talking about
stuff where you have no permissions to
the to the data uh that's being affected
and and I just want to um clarify on
that. You said unauthenticated. Um, and
I'm I'm curious whether that means
unauthenticated as in I have no cookies
or unauthenticated as in I have no
rights to this organization, but I I
still am able to use like a self-signup,
you know, GCP account.
>> No rights to the organization.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, great. So, it doesn't really
necessarily matter whether I'm logged
into Google or or, you know, as long as
I I don't have access to the data at
all. I'm not in the or then that would
fall a little bit closer to S0 as long
as it's accessing data, right?
>> Yeah. Yep. That's 100% correct. I will
say like there's always like something
that you talked about earlier like the
discretion while we're clear it like we
our overriding goal is to always like
fairly and consistently reward
researchers.
>> So we have had reports where it seems
like IORE attacks. So like always s0
>> uh in this case it was a hey we can
exfiltrate the time you started training
a model
and I think this person like we went
back and forth arguing maybe like five
or six appeals uh before we had to say
like no this is just like you're right
technically it could be s0 but what are
you going to do with that information?
Uh and the answer is really nothing. It
doesn't lead to anything. Uh, it should
be fixed 100%. But it has to go to that
S2 level. It doesn't necessarily the
impact isn't there for like a I think
our lowest S0 is like 7500.
>> Okay. I'm I'm writing some notes on
that. Uh, okay. That makes sense. So, we
we're understanding S0 is is a little
bit more no rights to the org. S1, you
know, we've got uh some rights to the
org, you know, or the project or the
entity uh and then we're we're bypassing
those. And then S2 is some things that
should be fixed but have smaller
security impact. Um and then when we
move from server side bugs to client
side bugs, we're now in the C arena. Um
where we have C0 and C1. Can you explain
a little bit about that?
>> Yeah, C in this case stands for client
side. um it's kind on the top half of
the table. It could be service side or
severity. You could use either or
>> but um C 0C1 is severity levels or
client side issues.
>> Um so we actually see those a little bit
more rarely on cloud VRP. Um, but C 0 uh
C 0 and C1 are still a little bit
generalized. Um, compared to our S
categories up top in the table. Um,
actually be helpful if we could kind of
point to it right now. But
>> yeah, I can share my screen. Hold on.
There we go.
>> Sure.
>> I I should have I should have shared it
before. That that would have been
better. We we also try to we also try
to, you know, um
>> keep it largely audio compatible for the
audio listeners, but we can we can show
here, you know. So we've got S0 right
here this these categories and then S1
down here we've got you know some access
to the organization and these are
defined in these headers area right
right here and then we've got um C 0 and
C1 down here which is um I guess I guess
the difference here would be executing
client side code versus other
exploitable client side issues where
you're getting excss or you're not
getting XSS it seems like right
>> yeah um in general our C0 is can you
execute code on the client
>> of your victim. That's essentially what
it is.
>> Um, and C1 is a little bit more of a
catch-all. Um,
>> so you know those XSS type
vulnerabilities
>> if you can demonstrate actual JavaScript
code execution uh that's impactful the
asterisk
>> can get you something that would qualify
for C0 which that that category does
still have a pretty high reward.
>> Yeah. $20,000 and and I imagine, you
know, an XSS on Google Cloud should have
a pretty high reward because of the of
the impact there. You know, if you can,
you know, if you get someone to click a
link and they're logged into you GCP,
you can get RCE on, you know, a lot of
their instances, right? You know, by by
just, you know, pushing client side
commands from the user's browser, you
know, through web shell or whatever, um,
or cloud shell.
>> Um, so that makes a lot of sense. Um,
and then up at the top, we've got our
tiering levels here. So, um, can you
guys talk a little bit about those and
how those affect the reward as well?
>> Yeah. Uh, these are pretty
straightforward. It's basically there
there's like an internal algorithm that
goes basically like by the
revenue and how many people are using it
and the API calls and a lot of things
that go into say like how much basically
it's incentivizing people to we want to
find more
vulnerabilities in our tier one
products. This is our way to incentivize
like hey you should be hacking on on
this more. So the IT1 or tier one
products are the things that we I won't
say care most about but from like a we
want to incentivize the most amount of
research into where the IT3A which is
like acquisitions or like the IT3B which
is like if it's not in our table at all
and you find it there it's probably
going to be IT3B.
And I I'll I'd like to build on that a
little bit just to add on this is the
reason why we care about taring in terms
of security, right? We have in cloud
hundreds of products. Um Cotay mentioned
the number of users, right? So if if use
cloud storage as an example tier one
product because so many users
directly use cloud storage but also
other Google cloud products interact
with cloud storage right so this has a
wide attack service so when you find
impact in cloud storage as an as an
example of tier one you're finding that
it's more highly impactful than a tier
three product that maybe is only used in
one product. Uh it's not used
crosscloud, maybe has a smaller user
base. Right? So this is why we employ
taring in our rewards table.
>> That makes sense. Okay. So, and one of
the things that I'll shout out here and
I think I've mentioned on the pod
before, but from personal experience,
you have to be very careful when you
are, you know, hacking on Google
products because there could be a
certain section of the application where
it's a tier one, right? But then a sub,
you know, application of that or like a
subcomponent of that is a tier three,
right? And that and that drastically
changes your um your reward that you
would get for for hacking on that. Um,
so I just wanted to shout that out to
the listener as well. And and I think
there's a really cool opportunity here
for either the Google VRP team or some
member of the community to write a a
plug-in that parses, you know, the tier
the tier list that is listed in in
Google's scope or in their policy here
and and allows you to understand, okay,
what product am I likely on right now?
what tier am I hacking on? Um for any
given um HTTP request, but also for, you
know, when you're looking in the
application, you could have it in, you
know, a Chrome extension or something
like that as well. That could be really
cool.
>> Yeah, love that idea. And if anybody
watching here wants to do that, our tier
list is public.
Let us know. Um and yeah, we've uh we
we've talked a lot about taring
internally as well, Justin. And you know
on the topic of us taking feedback uh
one of our colleagues specifically is
working on kind of updating and
consolidating some of our tiers
>> product tiers.
>> Um for for example right now to your
point we have a lot of kind of
subproducts and features that are
different tiers. It's
>> it's a lot to manage for our researchers
and that's the last thing that we want
is to make it harder to hack on Google.
Right.
>> Yeah. It's a little bit of a it's a
little bit of both though I think for
the listener just to be honest with you
guys is like this adds complexity but
this also is something for you to defeat
as the hacker right you know you you
because of the complexity other hackers
are going to have difficulty with it too
you know and and that difficulty leads
to more untouched scope and and that
difficulty leads to less people being
willing to put in the work and frankly
the top earners in bug bounty that I've
ever seen hack cloud products
Um, and so this is where you know, you
know, Google Cloud, AWS, Azure, you
know, all of those are ripe targets for
making yourself a very very high earning
hacker. Um, and and so you guys got to
be up to the up for the challenge.
>> It also the complexity
it also adds complexity for us
>> like the interconnectedness of all our
products. So I think do you mind me
talking about you? I think what? No, go
for it.
>> Your Vegas event uh specifically I
remember there was a lot of talk about
it back and forth in the panel because
>> say you were on SEC I believe.
>> Yeah, I was. Yep.
>> And you basically like we have a suite
of tools like not all of our products
have a suite of tools but this one does.
And you clicked on something and we
you're like hey like I thought this is
part of SEC and we talked a lot about in
the panel of oh man like what from a
user perspective if a user was going and
clicking on this would what would they
expect? Would they expect you to be like
no it's not an SEC product but I'm in
that product clicking on the links. What
do you mean it's not SEC? Ultimately, it
was like one very hard decision, but we
ultimately decided like just from a
fairness and like like how do you know
because that's also a standalone
product,
>> right?
>> How do we determine from a rewards
perspective fairly and consistently
like what a product is and then we
ultimately decided it has to be the
route I think for that for the event uh
because you know it's a researcher
event. I think we rewarded you like the
like the bonus and all that of being in
scope but that made us like rethink the
other part is
S1 F is like single service S1C is like
multi-ervice that interconnectedness and
like the impersonations and the service
accounts that you can achieve and like
because of all that interconnectedness
can raise rewards for researchers
>> there's a lot more opportunity because
of that to go from one service to
another and when that happens we reward
more. Yeah, certainly, you know, that
out that outcome for me in that event I
was happy with and and I think largely
overall, you know, despite there's some
confusion and some duress, you know,
like I've like or being stressed out a
little bit about it, you know, at the
end of the day, we talk through it, you
know, and and we get resolution and I
I've been happy very happy overall with
the outcome of my reports, right? Um,
which I think is is is is different than
a lot of programs. You know, some
programs it's just clean cleancut, you
know, and you just, you know, it it fits
in a box and you pay the bounty and
whatever, right? In some other program
it it's, you know, you're you're
fighting for for every single little
thing and and stuff like that and or
your voice isn't heard, right? Um, one
of the things I really do appreciate
about Google is we have a good amount of
back and forth and I I never don't feel
heard. You know, if I'm not happy with
the outcome, you damn well know I'm
hurt, though. You know, like,
>> hell yeah. No, we I mean, appeal like if
if you don't think that your reward is
fair or your rationale does not make
sense, let us know. I mean
>> all of every researcher's appeal comes
back in front of the panel which
consists of myself Cotay and a swath of
other security engineers on cloud and we
will do our best to either re-evaluate
make sure that we got it right and also
explain it to you in a way that makes
sense.
>> Yeah.
>> Like we we don't always get it right.
Right. We're people at the end of the
day. Um and we rely on our researchers
expertise for a reason. That's why we
have bug bounty. Yeah,
>> I'll add like our panel is super
empathetic to researchers. Like I I
think that you know half our panel maybe
uh were researchers and hacking on
Google before Google hired them. Um one
of the people on the panel like when
again there it's very nuanced way more
than I would like but he will frequently
say like when we're advocating between
two different ones it's like like
5,00075 he's like I'm he always says I'm
always happy to pay the researcher more.
>> Yeah. Like I would honestly pay every
single report, but we would go
absolutely bankrupt. It wouldn't be fair
to everybody else who's not getting
that. But like it has to be consistent.
>> Yeah. No, that makes a lot of sense and
and I I I think that's a great point,
you know, and I know for sure the
hackers that you're talking about that
are on your panel, you know, that that
are excellent hackers and are actively
hacking on bug bounting programs while
they work at Google, you know. Um, so
it's definitely good to have hacker
representation there. Um,
>> last thing I'll say about tier as well,
um,
>> I would urge our researchers to not be
afraid to start on our tier three
products, right? Like, yes, the rewards
are lower,
>> but to Cote's point, those lower tier
products can lead you to higher tier
product impact because of the
interconnectedness.
And also, I mean,
yeah, t tier three does reward less, but
it's you can get a pretty high reward.
We just rewarded a 50k payout on a tier
three bug just the other day, right? So,
which is nothing to scoff at.
>> Yeah, totally. Um, I think that's a
great point. And I also wanted to ask
you about transitions between tiers
because if I remember correctly at one
of the live hacking events that I've
been to, there was somebody who was able
to compromise some serious data. Um, and
it technically was an acquisition, but
that acquisition had been integrated
fully into a a higher tier product, it
seemed. Um, and I'm not sure where that
report landed on the tier table, but the
bounty was great, you know. Um, so at
what point does an acquisition move, you
know, from an acquisition to a higher
tier product upon integration?
>> We actually just recently wrote an an
internal precedent on this. Um, it's
it's not publicized because it's it it's
kind of rough, right? I mean, Google's
buying products left and right.
>> Yeah. U but it's rough like roughly I
think threeish years
uh after acquisition which is kind of a
fuzzy date to begin with sometimes we'll
kind of just consider the product um for
a higher tier it won't be in that IT3A
category.
>> Okay that's great that's good to know.
Yeah. And I and I think just as a you
know for the listeners um yeah I mean
look look at these full integrations you
know where everything is under a a high
tier product you know but but the code
you know or the implementation
underlying is is telling you a different
story you know like I think you guys
know what I'm talking about where stuff
is kind of you know duct taped together
and and you you see that I mean even
with Google you see you see it because
especially when you got a company that
is buying a lot of like you guys do. Um,
very
>> and there's a reason why like there's an
ITA or IT3A because they're not on the
the Google stack we consider much more
hardened than like many of our
acquisitions. So there is like
>> less rewards probably more opportunity.
>> Totally. Yeah, that's a great point. Um
>> I will say I mean even our older
acquisitions
uh hot tip look into those products.
>> Yeah. Oh for sure. there are bugs to be
found.
>> Um, that's great. Let's let's I'm glad
for you clarifying all that. Let's take
a second and talk about the panel and
then we'll jump back over to some
success tips um with with hacking on
GCP. Um, so we've talked a little bit
about the panel process in the past. Um,
for the viewer that hasn't seen those
episodes, uh, the way that reports are,
um, and you guys can feel free to
interrupt me or or correct my
explanation at any point, but the way
that this works is uh, a team of
Googlers come together. they review a a
group of reports um in in a meeting and
that's how the um you know bounties are
deliberated and it normally comes to uh
a unanimous consensus right among among
the team and you get the reward and then
when you appeal those appeals also go
back up to the panel and the panel
reviews the your your case they review
the the reward and they decide one way
or the other to make a decision on that.
Um, how is that explanation? Did you
guys have anything to add there or
modify?
>> Yeah, I will say it's not usually uh
100% agreement. It's always 100%
agreement. We require it to move
forward. Uh there's a lot of debate.
I'll say the also like of interest would
be to your research community like the
person leading that panel will take
about like four to six hours going
through maybe 15 reports
uh that we want to discuss within panel.
So like significant amount of
understanding for each before actually
getting to panel. So they dived in and
like hey like they were able to get this
service account like who generally has
it like what can they do with it
>> uh what data is available from it. So
there's a lot that goes into every
single report. Um quite a bit of time uh
but again appeal as much as you want. It
goes right back to the same panel.
>> Yeah. And that and that analysis is on
top of the initial triage that happens
on your bug where the issue is
reproduced and assessed by a second team
and then assessed again by the product
team. Right. So this is almost like a
fourth layer of review that your report
goes through before it gets a reward.
>> Awesome. Yeah, that makes sense. Okay,
so we've got the panel. Um I do have
some some more questions about that, but
first let's let's let's jump back. Um, I
wanted to talk to you guys a little bit
about like the recommendations for the
researcher on getting these services
configured and and getting data in them
and stuff like that because I know you
mentioned with the live hacky event
there's a lot of scope that you need
like enterprise access to you know um
you you need data from you know all
these different sources to get populated
to be able to do testing. Um what kind
of tips do you have for us on that
front?
Yeah, on
quick caveat. I mean again cloud is kind
of a little bit difficult to to get into
in my opinion
>> as opposed to like Android or something,
right? I mean most people know how to
use a phone.
>> You kind of have a baseline knowledge.
>> Um for cloud it's usually businesses
>> who are directly interacting with cloud
products, right? So it it can be harder
to get into if you've never used a cloud
product. Luckily, Terraform exists. Um,
I would use ter and Terraform has a lot
of code samples, especially for our core
products, um, to quickly spin up
instances like GKE, especially really
difficult product to get into. If you're
not familiar, um, employ Terraform,
uh, use our setup documentation not only
to make your life easier, but also from
a rewards perspective. The more closely
you as a hacker are matching the common
customer kind of environment, the more
successful you'll be.
>> Yes.
>> Right. That's
>> and we added
>> we we added a special downgrade
um in our rewards update from last
September to capture some of these
cases. Right. So we were we were seeing
some of our researchers submit reports
with a really wacky kind of
configuration that we'd never seen
before. We know not very many of our
customers actually use use the product
the way in which the hacker is using it
which I mean still a valid issue but
it's not going to be as impactful on
Google cloud right if you're not using
the product in the way that most
customers are right that that's the
whole
>> um so following our user guides I mean I
don't I don't want to say that our user
guides are perfect and will help you and
help you understand the the back end. Uh
but as far as getting started on Google
Cloud, definitely start there. Um and
your rewards will be higher if you find
a bug that way.
>> Yeah. And and and I'll also just add to
that for the listener like that is a big
part of the challenge for this scope.
Like like don't be afraid to spend a lot
of time configuring the product. Like I
think a lot of hackers get antsy when
they're not churning through attack
vectors, right? you know, um, and I
totally get that, but you got to
understand with these products that are
that, um, are very, you know, deep, you
you got to spend a lot of time
configuring, getting data in,
understanding before you can actually
start understanding what kind of attack
vectors are valid, uh, or even being
able to idate properly on attack
vectors. Um, I think that's really a
really important piece. Um, Cot, did you
have any Oh, Darby, do you have another
comment here?
>> Yes, sorry. Um,
>> go for it. to add on to that to what you
just said um not a lot of hackers I
think are spending that time to dig deep
into the product which means cloud
uh probably has a lot of bugs uh ready
for the taking and our top researchers
who are getting these 50 75 100k reports
are the ones who have dug deep into our
especially our newer products right like
the AI products looks like Vert.ex,
Agent Space, XYZ, they have a deep
understanding of how that works. They
spend time reviewing our documentation,
finding holes.
>> Um, and then they find a swath of
issues, right? So, that kind of upfront
load of learning the product. Yeah.
>> I've seen researchers, right, they get
started on cloud, they start on a
certain product and then we get five or
six reports and they're all valid,
right? So some of that upfront work can
really lead to big payouts in the end
and especially because not not a lot of
people are putting in that upfront time.
>> Totally. Cot thoughts?
>> No, she dar nailed it.
>> That's perfect. Yeah, I think that I
think there's a lot of nuance to these
in systems, but one of the biggest ones
is put in the time, understand the app,
get data in there, you'll see the attack
vectors coming through.
>> Um, that's great y'all. Jumping back to
um the the panel a little bit. I know
we're we're getting all over the place,
but we're back on track.
>> Um you jumping back to the panel, I had
a grill you question on this.
>> You know, you mentioned this this
person, I think in the past you've
called them the DJ that is running these
these panels. Um, as far as I understand
it, when a a report comes in, you it
gets assigned to a specific cue off the
bat, you know, and and maybe this would
be a good question as well for Google
VRP and abuse, but um, one of the things
that I've seen is, you know, that that
cue that it gets assigned to in the
beginning, a representative from that
organization will be the DJ that is
assessing, you know, and and explaining
these bugs to the panel, right? Um and
and I'm wondering whether that under
that that results in the depth that
we're that we need as hackers to get the
DJ and the panel to understand the
specific vulnerability that we have. For
example, if I submit a bug, it goes to
abuse Q and it's a and it you know
because it's a I don't know something
that triggers abuse. For example, for a
little while your prompt injections all
prompt injections went to abuse Q,
right? Um the then you know we have
abuse explaining a GCP bug to the panel
which I'm not super confident is is the
best thing. Um can you explain some
nuance there or am I missing something
or is that how it is?
>> Uh so for when we I call it panel shop.
So like first like why do we do this?
Typically when we send to another panel,
so like anything cloud comes to us just
right off the bat. If we have to send to
abuse, abuse has their own DJ,
they have their own like technical,
they're going to do the same in-depth
analysis uh as we would on those bugs
and we're very comfortable with like
security engineers diving in the impact
and understanding their rewards tier. So
like we always have to be consistent
with our rewards. And the reason I know
like we have a lot of from our top
researchers like I get like this
question more than others. Like why are
you sending to abuse? Why are you
sending to OSS? Like your rewards are
slightly higher. I want it in your
panel. The answer is like that's the
only way we can get you paid at that
point. Like it doesn't fit in our table
or it's a very lower reward. Like it's
within our table because we have to be
consistent within our table. We are
going to pay you low. We if it's
possible that you will get paid more
from another panel, we always give it to
them to only give researchers more
money. Like that is
>> I hear that. I hear that. Cot I'm going
to push back on that a little bit though
because what happens you know from from
our perspective is a report gets comes
in and it gets sorted to a specific
queue. That's not the queue we want in
the in the in this scenario, right?
Let's say it get you know I'm hoping for
GCP it gets routed to abuse. you know
GCP unless abuse says GCP might pay this
more then GCP never sees it right
>> correct but we're we work
>> doesn't know about GCP
>> they don't understand the product level
you know I mean and all these all these
people are Google engineers so
>> they're all Google security engineers in
which case like again it's about
>> adherence to their like their tier and
they understand their rewards table and
their rewards criteria much more better
than we ever will. Like
>> they understand and they understand like
our rewards table and they the only
reason they're sending to somebody else
is to maximize the rewards for the
researcher. That is 100% uh the reason
>> unless it gets sorted incorrectly in the
beginning though, right?
>> I want to clarify that part. So the
sorting incorrectly in the beginning is
>> I'm going to say nearly impossible,
right? Of course, this is this is being
done by humans. But if your report is
concerning cloud or a cloud product,
which by the way, we have a large swath,
it will enter our queue.
>> Okay.
>> Um
even if the initial triager, which by
the way is like level zero, so this is
like even a fifth level of review, is
they are not going to assess that
initial impact. They're like, "Hey, is
this cloud? send it on to the cloud of
people and then when it gets to our
panel we will decide on a reward and at
that point it can be sent to abuse if we
don't think that we can reward under our
table. So that the case that that you're
talking about this example where a bug
is initially entering some other VRP's
queue like open-source abuse
um and then being routed to cloud
usually not the case. Um abuses uh we're
we're typically routing to them versus
them routing to us.
>> Yeah, that makes sense. And and I think
maybe I'll get some other
representatives from the other parts of
Google as well on here because I think
this issue like you said relates to them
a little bit more than it relates to you
because GCP is is GCP, you know, and
they're going to route it to GCP, right?
And then you're going to send it back to
abuse. Um um so yeah, I I I I think that
makes sense and I I I know that your
your overall um you know disposition uh
is to try to get the hacker rewarded. So
if it if it can't get rewarded on our
GCP, then you send it to abuse. You send
it to somebody else to see if it can. Um
I'm just worried about those situations.
And as a hacker, I would like to have a
little bit more of a locus of control of
I want GCP eyes on this on this, you
know, bug or I I want I want Google VPIs
on this bug even if it gets routed to
abuse right off the bat. I don't want
abuse saying, "Hey, this isn't us. This
is Google." You know, I want Google
saying, "This isn't us. This is abuse."
Does that make sense?
>> Thank you, by the way. So the initial
the initial routing that is exactly how
it happens. So someone within the Google
VRP makes a determination
>> and it's super easy to send between the
the different panels. So like they make
the initial L0 as JY called it. They
make the initial determination. It's
immediately looked at between on that
abuse or cloud or Google and because we
reproduce every issue that comes in. we
say like oh is this they so they have to
do a confirmation because we're not
qualified to
reproduce issues that are not really for
us and assess the the impact of it and
so we'll immediately reroute it to those
like appropriate uh programs
>> I see and I'll add I think um you as a
researcher have control here okay like
>> oh I thought you were talking about me
as a researcher for a second I was like
oh [__] why are they talking about me as
a researcher I know I'm Not a good boy.
I know Darby like you know. Yeah.
>> You and everybody else you you meaning
the community have control over some
control over your report, right? Like if
if you are not pleased with the result,
right? You see that panel decision and
it says the abuse vulnerability rewards
panel and you're like what the heck? I
wanted this right
>> rated under the clouds table. Um you can
post a comment on the bug. you can
appeal and say, "Hey, respectfully,
>> Mhm.
>> this seemed to have cloud security
impact. I think it might fit under this
category in their rewards table. Could
this be sent to the cloud VRP for
re-evaluation?"
>> More than likely, it'll make it over to
us. I mean, not not that that I've seen
that happen because I I don't think that
that misouting happens very often at
all, but you you as the researcher have
control over that, right? Every single
comment that you post is read by a
human. And if you have a problem, please
raise that.
>> Yeah, I will. Don't worry. I will. You
guys know I will. the la the last live
hack event that we had, you know, I
spent what probably an hour maybe, you
know, 45 minutes an hour sitting outside
of the the war room with, you know,
Darby and Cot like debating a bug for
both myself and another person because
of course, you know, when you when
you're a podcaster, people are like,
"All right, that dude can talk. Go
advocate for my bug," you know. Um, so
we had great conversations and uh and
landed at a good spot, I think. Um so uh
the next question that I wanted to ask
was 60 minute 60-minute panel 15 15 bugs
four minutes a bug
you know you guys get a lot of you guys
get a lot of thoroughut in in the in the
Google program how often are you doing
these panels how often do you get
through all all 15 bugs in 60 minutes um
and and how does that affect like your
pipeline getting you
backfilled a little bit and affecting
SLAs's.
>> So, we have two panels a week. Uh, one
like with the European time zones and
one like more American time zones uh to
try and get through as many as we can.
We I will say normally we don't get
through 15. I'll say the easiest ones
are like if it's obviously low impact,
obviously high impact. These are really
easy. I think the thing that bogs us
down are the ones that are like hey this
is
oh like discussing whether it's working
as intended like a lot of these and
again something you mentioned earlier
about digging into the product if you
can point to product documentation about
like why you believe something isn't
working the way it should be like that
is like the one of the best arguments
that you can make uh on our panel
because we do take into consideration
like what would the average user think
like are they going to expect that you
can for with this privilege
escalate to this other thing? And if the
admin like a lot of times that's why we
downgrade the heck out of like if you
start with admin because usually the
answer is yes but if you can point to
documentation where it specifically says
like this is our security boundary. We
were just going through this another one
and like you would not expect this then
you're going to much more likely your
case is very good to get rewarded.
That's a great point. Um, yeah, I think
that's I think that's valuable to
understand for the researcher and and I
I did want to circle back around as well
to the, you know, nature of the panel
shop uh and and whether that is
different from the actual panel. Um, can
can you speak to that a little bit?
>> The panel shop. Yeah. So like we
typically or the whoever it's initially
assigned to will definitely generally
make a recommendation of like hey we
think this is and usually it's credit or
working as intended within the product
but imagine it's like a billing abuse
issue that doesn't really fall within
our rewards criteria typically 100%
should be rewarded or not not rewarded
but fixed but we can't really pay it in
adherence to our table. Then we'll say,
"Hey, abuse, we think this is credit
because XYZ for our panel. Will you be
able to pay it? Here are like the the
basic TLDDR of the impact and of the
issue. Please make it uh an assessment
yourself."
>> Okay. Okay. So, we've got panel and then
we, you know, it goes to the panel shop
if we're if and is that a panel as well
or is that just like
>> Okay.
>> Another panel like it'll go to their
abuse panel or the OSS channel. Darby,
you you look like you disagreed with
what he just said.
>> Panel shop Yeah.
>> is not its own panel. Panel shopping is
like an action that Cotay is talking.
>> Oh, I see. Okay.
>> I think that's that was where you're
misunderstanding me because Yeah. So
when when Cotay says panel shop, he
means like in our normal panel meetings,
if we can't reward it, we will panel
shop and figure out where it can be
rewarded.
>> Okay. Okay. So then you'll you'll pass
it to other panels for
>> rewarding. Same group of people.
Excellent. Okay, that makes sense. Um,
let me see if I can if I can pull up
another another question here
specifically relating to the panel
before we move on to um, yeah, I think
we're going to go back a little bit to
to the policy. And I also want to give
you guys some some free form time uh,
you know, after we get through a couple
of these questions to talk about like
how hackers can start optimizing their
reports when when writing reports and
and that sort of thing. And you guys,
looking at the doc here, you guys did a
ton of prep for how like tips on how
hackers can get rewarded more for their
for their um reports, which is
excellent. Um before we get to that
though, I would like to do talk about
downgrades and upgrades or um you know,
additional uh rewards on top of your
report bonuses. That's the word. Um can
you explain
what things might result in a downgrade
that we should avoid? Um and and then uh
we'll transition to how our reports can
be extraordinary and receive uh you know
1.2x multiplier.
>> Sorry.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um yeah, common downgrades
involve what prior access the attacker
had, right? In this hypothetical
scenario that you're reporting to us
that the attacker needs in order to
perform the exploit. Um, I see you have
kind of user interaction here as an
example. That's another one. So, this is
beyond the behavior that the user would
normally take in the product, right? Is
it clicking on a link, clicking on a
button that's kind of not normally seen
on the screen, we could downgrade for
that as additional interaction that just
it makes it harder for the attacker to
successfully exploit
um the victim's environment. Let me let
me jump through a couple of these and
I'll ask pointed questions about each.
So the first one is impact. That's one
step down. Applied for minor impact.
Subjective, you know, but hopefully our
our reports are are showing good impact.
And maybe we could bolster this by
writing our impact section very
thoroughly, right? Um prior prior
access, we talked about that one. User
interaction. The one that I I did want
to highlight here in this one was uh
this quote right here. this applies to
interaction beyond the normal usage of
the affected product. Okay. Um that is a
really awesome statement to to make uh
because sometimes there are things that
require user interaction but that is
really like natural in the in the
product. For example, this wasn't GCP
but I had a scenario where um I had a
bug and you know the user would submit a
ticket. As soon as the person processing
the ticket clicked the ticket, something
would happen, you know, but then they're
they're counting that as user
interaction like I had them come to my
malicious attacker page, you know.
>> Was that a client side attack?
>> It was. It was. Yeah. So, I mean there's
there's there's difference there as
well, right? But um you know delivery
mechanisms do change throughout these
these things and if it I I believe that
user interaction should either have
multiple tiers or if user interaction is
required and that is an essential part
of the product that that shouldn't be
counted against the researcher. What
what is Google's thought on that
scenario? Interestingly enough, for like
client side attacks, it's typically and
it may or may not be uh documented on
this page, but we generally consider
like full payment
immediately upon opening. There are rare
cases where you're like, hey, everyone
does this like and that is to get full.
We usually only see like user
interaction or primarily with these
client side attacks where it takes one
or two additional clicks where we
consider most client side attacks like
as soon as you open it you're you're
already done
>> for
these other like your exact scenario we
have removed it when it's such a common
use case that like as soon you're just
not brainwashed but like conditioned to
as soon as you open this link you're
going to a dashboard you must click this
button and that's your always your
workflow. In that case, it depends, but
sometimes we'll remove that user
interaction.
>> I love that. I love that because that
also speaks to a high quality PC, right?
One of the things that's crazy about the
whole G GDRP thing um is that people
always click except cookie, you know,
without even thinking, you know, and so
that's one of the ways that I think
hackers have harvested
a required click without even using, you
know, your brain in some of those
scenarios, right? What what what do you
guys think about that? Like if a user
has a really high quality PC where
you're just, you know, like you said,
brainwashed into clicking this button,
>> call it out. like make your case like
honestly like
there are 300 uh products we get reports
on plus make the best case you can the
easier you make it for like hey the
impact the attack preconditions all of
this like and I think we're going to go
into that uh later but make it easy sell
like hey this is just normal everyday
workflow the product only works this way
if once you open this you click it uh
And we'll have to review of course, but
that makes a much better case than just
saying you do this uh and you let then
the panel basically decide your fate.
>> I like that. So that is taken well into
consideration. I like that. Um and I
think that's another reason why us as
researchers, just speaking to the
community here, we should have a toolkit
for these sort of things. Like we should
there should be a GitHub repo out there.
I don't know how we don't have this that
has a you know GDPR accept cookie button
that you know you can easily I frame you
know clickj into clicking whatever you
want you know like that that should
totally be happening. Um so
we need to build that. Um all right
exploitability is the next one. It says
downgrade applied because the attack is
still possible but the vulnerability is
difficult to exploit in practice. What
is what is difficulty to exploit? What
does difficult to exploit mean here? Um,
Darby, if you if you could take this
one.
>> Yeah, 100%. Um, this is another one of
those kind of subjective ones. So, this
is beyond user interaction, but um I
mean it's it's anything that just
decreases the likelihood of a victim
being exploited, right? This is uh kind
of a likelihood downgrade. Um,
uh,
>> okay. So, specific conditions,
preconditions for the attack perhaps or
>> Yeah. Yeah. I'm I'm trying to think of
some examples, but um, precondition is a
great example. So, uh, this is aside
from prior access and user interaction,
but like if the if the victim has to
have some um setting enabled.
>> Yeah. or like maybe it only affects
victims with, you know, an uppercase
letter in their username or something
like that. Is that a good example of
that?
>> Great great example, right, of the the
victim's environment has to be in a very
specific state
>> for the exploit to be possible. Um, so
like maybe a timebased attack,
>> if there's a limited window where the
exploit succeeds, that's where we might
use this downgrade.
>> What if that is the case? But we've
created a really reliable like race
condition exploit.
>> If it's listen, even if it's reliable,
>> we're basing this off of the standard
use case for whatever affected product
we're talking about, right? So yeah, if
the majority of Google Cloud customers,
you know, this setting, for example, is
>> well, that's a little bit more uncommon
configuration, right? Rather than
exploitability or is that
exploitability?
uh they're linked but different. Um like
if if we're talking about a setting that
is not enabled by default, needs to be
enabled, it's not necessarily an
uncommon configuration because it's
already like an available setting in the
product. But now we're just kind of
splitting hairs. But uh
>> let let me ask let me ask one maybe
something that would clarify between the
two if I may. So, so what I'm trying to
get at here is one of the things that
really hurts the heart of the researcher
is a scenario where the attack is very
complex, but we've done it. We've
threaded the needle. We've created the
exploit that works really well. And
yeah, it does. You know, it's complex as
heck, you know, but what I'm asking is
will we we be downgraded for threading
the needle here because it's an ex a a a
difficult attack scenario and only, you
know, a limited set of attackers would
have the capability to to exploit that.
>> The short answer is no. You will not be
downgraded for that. M
>> um this is meant to capture limitations
on um on the victim side, right? Like
how many available
customers are actively in a state where
they might be exploited by this
vulnerability, right? So even if you're
the only attacker in the world who knows
how to do this, you have insane skills
and your pock is super complex and you
threaded the needle. If only a hundred
Google Cloud customers are operating in
the very specific state that's needed to
make this vulnerability exploitable,
then that's that's on a lower tier than
maybe a 100,000 customers being actively
vulnerable.
>> Sure. Okay.
>> Those are cases where we might use this
downgrade.
>> That makes sense. So you guys are using
some metrics on your side to to
determine what amount of customers are
in this con this state and that is what
contributes to uh exploitability.
Whereas uncommon configuration
is something where you know you look at
the documentation and this is not like a
configuration that you guys are
particularly you know encouraging uh or
you allow the product to be configured
in that way but it's not something that
that is recommended and and that is
where we get the uncommon configuration
downgrade.
>> Yeah. Correct. Like an an example of
that might be you're using some super
niche uh extension in in your product.
Uh, right that maybe only five of our
customers are using. Um, that might be
an example of uncommon configuration.
>> Yeah. A good example of exploitability
might be like bucket squatting where in
some cases like hey as soon as you
>> uh instantiate the product this bucket
is created and you need to go the
customer needs to go and delete the
bucket
and then it's squattable but only maybe
in the time window between you go and
try and reuse that same like feature
which would automatically recreate it.
And so you have to
convince somehow social engineering or
they just have to do it and you have to
know and you have to do it again before
they use the feature. If all those have
to be true then like exploitability
would be the docy bit.
>> Uh that makes sense. Okay that that
makes sense. And as far as uncommon
configuration goes what are some um
things that we can provide as the
researcher to avoid this downgrade? like
if we can we provide you with um
documentation, sample code, you know,
that sort of thing and and will that
help us avoid that?
>> Yeah, 100%. I mean, we we don't even
mind if you link if you quote our own
documentation at us
>> in your report, if you say, "Hey, your
own documentation recommends that
customers configure their product in
this way." So,
>> just by the way, in case you were
thinking that this was uncommon, which
it might look like it is at the surface,
uh your documentation specifically
encourages customers to do that, which
inherently makes it a common
configuration then for our customers. M
>> um yeah, so feel free to parrot back our
documentation at us or even um I mean
even if it's not provided by us, we'd be
happy to kind of look into some
resources that you found that
>> um
>> that's a great point. If like this the
top like Stack Overflow answer or
something like has that then then maybe
we this all contributes to the
likelihood that that configuration will
be put in place.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Very very good. I like that. That that's
excellent. and and um yeah, I think that
understanding those those nuances and
going the extra mile to configure stuff
uh and in the way that um is is
consistent not only res reduces your
risk of getting uncommon configuration,
but it also helps with like getting the
setup done, right? So just really follow
the guides, you know, set up the product
like that rather than going in there and
trying to figure it out yourself and
getting yourself into some weird, you
know, configuration and then you'll
avoid uncommon configuration downgrade
and it'll make your setup easier.
>> That's important like you have to put it
in the YOLO mode for it to work.
>> Yeah, might be an uncommon configuration
that we might expect. So things of that
nature.
>> Yeah. Okay. That that makes a lot of
sense. Um, moving moving from those
downgrades then over to uh upgrades or
bonuses. We have novelty um as as an uh
upgrade which I I imagine is you know a
novel type of attack that you guys
haven't seen. I don't know that that one
needs much uh discussion, but the report
quality dimensions I think are are
really interesting piece of Google and
um and essentially what you guys have
here for the audio listeners that we're
sharing on the screen is a a matrix of
um you know characteristics of your
report and you your report will be
downgraded you know by point you know to
point8 uh 80% of what it would have been
um if it doesn't if it really really is
missing all of these pieces Right? And
you know the normal is is you know 1x,
right? So you're just going to get the
value, but you also have the ability to
write an exceptional report which will
get you an extra 20% on top of your
report if we check all of these boxes.
Um so what are what are some tips from
you guys? Maybe Cot can answer this one.
um on how to like write a an exceptional
report here because some of these, you
know, some of these are built into your
template that you provide us when we're
submitting a report, but some of them
are not. And I'm wondering whether
that's intentional, you know, trying to
get people to pay extra attention or or
what's going on.
>> So, and I find this interesting because
I have one example in a little bit, but
the read it and know it. I I know
researchers spend I think we did some
research on like something like 16 hours
finding a vulnerability or report and
sometimes more the report is such a
small percentage of that like go through
like we often see like missing attack
preconditions like we might downgrade
you uh if you call out that it's admin
but we're going to figure that out
anyways because we're going to have to
reproduce your your report.
Make sure you're hitting all these like
notice is not like the vulnerability
description. It's not like amazing
quality. It's effectively described. We
want you to be short and to the point.
Um I'll also say like the more you use
AI,
>> typically the like the longer your
report gets, uh our goal here is to like
as quickly as possible be able to
reproduce, assess, and reward you. the
better that you do, the more likely we
are to be able to reward you effect like
quickly with the maximum amount with
that bonus. So recently, last week, we
had someone say, "Hey,
there's this report on your site that
got 225. I only got a small like 13 uh
12. What was the difference?" And I had
to say, "They got exceptional. It was
when it was at 1.5 and you got low
quality
and $105,000 for what probably was like
an hour of their time is a lot of money
especially after all of the time that
they put into the report. So go through
I we actually and Darby led it like she
actually led uh part of it like redoing
all of the exceptional report quality
and redoing those like downgrades we
just went over. But go over them, make
sure they're all in there, make sure
you're like short and to the point and
succinct and you can get that like 1.2.
And we've specifically redid it so that
everyone can get it.
>> Like previously it was like you had to
know like provide a like how do you fix
it? And with some of these server side
you might not know.
>> Now everyone should be able to get that
1.2 every single time. We absolutely
like you benefit and we benefit when you
get that. That's crazy because you guys
your bounties are already super good and
then you just you're tacking on an
additional 20% for anybody who who even
who tries on their report because it's
like effectively described not like you
know flawless you know it's just
effectively
>> have your misspellings in there we don't
care like that's not what we're looking
for. We're looking for like how quickly
it is able to reproduce a report.
>> That's great.
>> Yeah. Some examples I've seen of
researcher reports, some some
researchers will they'll write a
sentence in the their initial report and
then just attach their full research
paper, 20 pages.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> Yeah. Like amazing work. Amazing work.
Hats off to you. However, the time that
it takes us to read through your 20page
research paper is I mean, frankly, it
it's money time wasted on on our end,
right? So, selfishly, it's to our
benefit to pay you a little bit of extra
time to put some of that extra work into
your report so that we can more quickly
understand the impact, reproduce, get
you a reward faster.
Um, so yes, it please feel free to
upload your research paper. Just know we
prefer not to read through the whole
thing. It will delay your reward.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Totally.
>> Let me add on there.
>> It's easy to miss stuff like, hey, when
you have like very succinct, hey, here's
the impact, here is the uh the attack
preconditions. If we have to read like
if your like P like your P or DBY calls
it a pock is like like super long that's
one thing. If all of the additional
words describing your attack are like 20
pages long we are 100% going to forget
maybe an important point that you're
making and not completely understand
perhaps the impact of your amazing
vulnerability.
>> Totally. Totally. Yeah, that makes a lot
of sense. Um, I I think it's it's hard
because that is definitely a skill, you
know, concise technical writing is not
easy, you know, but um it's something
that as bug hunters we need to get
better at in order to optimize these
rewards here. So, I'm sure they'll
figure out a way to to to milk the
system, you know, and and get these and
and I think I know for me, every time I
submit a report to Google, I look at
that table and I go through each point
and I make sure that I have each of
those, you know, there. And sometimes I
actually started doing this recently.
We'll see how it pans out. But I'll
actually put a section at the end of my
report, you know, and denote it as like,
you know, report quality standards and
document why I think that I I hit each
one of those, you know, and, you know,
who knows? Maybe that'll maybe that'll
uh that'll help.
>> I honestly I would love it if everyone
does that. It's a good reminder for us
and like it's at least we can more
effectively provide feedback.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's great. Um, I I did
want to ask as well, changing gears a
little bit, you know, GCP is an
enterprise product like you said, you
know, and and there's there's a lot of
businesses that are going to be using
it. It's it can get expensive. Um, one
of the things we've seen with other
cloud providers is the ability to for
testers to have accounts that are not
tied to their personal funds. you know
that they can spin up products, test
them and then and then you know spin it
down or whatever um and without that
going out of their their pocket. Do you
guys have something similar for that? Is
there any plans for that? Um how can we
test more effectively as researchers
without costing ourselves a bunch of
money?
>> You want to go Derby?
>> Sure. Yeah. And we we've been we've
gotten that feedback before. You're not
the first one. Um especially certain
enterprise level products. Yeah. kind of
impossible for independent researchers
to hack on. um we are essentially the
the short answer is we are working on a
way to get our researchers on these more
expensive products right either whether
it's provisioning uh Google cloud
credits which is basically like money
that can vouchers that can be added to
your billing account um
all the way to provisioning you guys
instances like a store instance to hack
on um at no cost to you. So we are we
are working on methods to get you guys
access to that. We saw the success of
that at our June bug spot last year. Um
so we know that it's it's an effective
way to get high criticality issues. Um
unfortunately it's a little bit of an
difficult internally
>> to get money
>> generating money out of thin air.
>> Yeah. Yeah. over to our our lovely
external researchers who are trying to
find security vulnerabilities in our
products.
>> Sounds great.
>> A little bit of a hard
>> cell
that if you have an enterprise product
like it's harder for credits uh we had
it internally approved and things
change. If you are a known researcher
uh and you want to hack on a enterprise
product, send Darby and I an email, send
us like a chat in Discord. Um we have
gotten multiple researchers access to
enterprise products both through bug
swap and outside. We want like new
research. We want to find these
vulnerabilities. So again, we we can't
do it for just anyone because like if
you haven't hacked on Google, like
there's no way to to check for like
abuse or fraud or whatnot, but if you
have a relationship with us, ask. We're
more than happy. Like maybe the product
says no. But that's the worst that
happens. We're definitely going to find
that. We're definitely going to ask them
if you want to hack on an enterprise
product. Uh we will do whatever we can
to make that happen.
>> That's excellent. Yeah, that's really
good. I I I think that definitely that's
a good opportunity for researchers and I
and it would be really cool to see if as
an established hunter, you know, you
reach a certain level reputation on bug
hunters.google.com or whatever and then
that entitles you to a certain amount of
credits. I think that could be I think
that could be a good system as well. Or
or maybe like it comes with a number of
uh accepted reports. you know, every
three accepted reports, you get X, you
know, dollars in credits to apply to
your account that you can use to find
more vulnerabilities.
I think that could be fun as well. Um,
all right. So, we've covered a lot of
what we wanted to cover. Um, I I do want
to go into some actual scenarios just
kind of talking through what that would
look like. But first, I want to give you
guys the opportunity to just dump on us
here the whole like prep that you did on
how to get these reports paid more. Um,
and there's like, you know, what is
this, five, six, seven paragraphs here
worth of of recommendations um that
users can use or, you know, hackers can
use to get their reports paid out the
max. Um, so I don't know if you guys
want to take these back and forth or if
one of you guys wants to take it
specifically. I'll leave it up to y'all.
>> Sure. Yeah. This kind of first big tip,
um, there's this concept that we use
internally, refer to internally as
privilege escalation delta.
>> Um, I'm sure somebody else on the
internet has used this term before, but
basically just refers to, I've mentioned
this earlier, where the attacker starts
versus where they finish. and that space
in between, right? If you start with
viewer access on the victim's project
and end with full project access, that's
a pretty big delta. You will get a high
reward for that. It's not
uh a big enough delta, right? If you
start with viewer access and you end
with viewer access, right? or maybe
viewer access on another product. Still
cross productduct impact but not as high
as full project takeover using those
just as examples. So in your report
when you're describing impact focus on
that where did I start when I began this
exploit? Where did I finish? What type
of data do I now have access to and in
which products?
>> That'll get you a higher reward. we will
downgrade um or upgrade your reward
based on those factors.
>> Yeah. Okay. So that's great. So we
should start we should have clearly
defined starts with this privilege ends
with this privilege. We could even make
that like a section in our report to
make it super clear and optimize the
bounty.
>> Yeah. 100%.
>> Awesome. All right. What's next?
>> Yeah, I'll jump around. Um, I'll just
say like clear attack scenarios like we
get a lot of reports and probably not
from your community which like like
really good hackers but some of these
and I was listening to one of your other
podcasts they were like oh is it a
realistic attack scenario or what do
they actually get out of it like the
example I used earlier like the billing
time like not billing but the time for
model train like like start and stop
times
>> do people
are attacker is going to take advantage
of that. If not, you're either going to
get really really downgraded or it's not
going to be rewarded at all as like it's
just not impactful.
>> So, think through it. Think through why
um and it might like stop a lot of back
and forth.
>> Why does the attacker maybe even making
this a section like we were saying, why
why does the attacker want to do this
attack?
>> Yes.
>> Very good.
Darby, back to you.
>> Yeah, I'll go to the next point. Um feel
free to in your report explain your
understanding of how the product is
supposed to work. Right? Our product
teams develop a product with a certain
intent of its use case. That does not
mean that it's always effectively
described to people outside of the
organization. Right? And sometimes uh we
can hit kind of a a disagreement there
where it's working as intended
internally but not necessarily as the
user would expect and that's a problem.
>> Yeah,
>> that that is a bug and and we want we
want those types of reports. Um but as a
hacker it's valuable to us if you
explain that perception of yours and why
you think this right. I got this
understanding that the project that the
product should work this way from your
own documentation, but based on the UI,
it seems to work this way. It's kind of
confusing. It could lead to victims
maybe misconfiguring some security
settings in their own environments.
That's a vulnerability. Um, so feel free
to explain that background in your
report. Yeah, I think that's a really
good differentiator there because um
yeah, the public perception of security
is is extremely you know important right
whether the user the user thinks that
this is uh you know this data is
accessible or not accessible informs
especially in a cloud product you know
their threat model for their apps you
know um as they're as you guys are a
building block of the applications that
these other businesses are are building
on Um I'm very glad that you guys have
that aligned um in your in your
policies. Um Cot, what do you have?
>> I'll just say uh mentioned it earlier,
but for the love of God, please stop
using AI to write your full report. Like
if you can't read your full report
because it's going to take you like 30
minutes. Uh and sometimes we've
literally gotten over a hundred comments
adding on to a singular bug. Uh there's
zero chance. like I am going to do
everything I can to like put that at low
because to basically disincentivize you
ever reporting like that again but go
through read it is it succinct is it
like you don't need AI for the most part
um and we much prefer succinct um the
other I'll just go right on but
>> we get a lot of questions about like hey
you started at S1 and now it's not
rewarded you started at S2 and now now
it's not rewarded like those are initial
assumptions again like Darby talked
about like how the product is expected
to work. So like a good and common
example about this is like hey yeah like
I was able to do something like the UI
prevents me to do something but using
like a CLI I was able to do it and
therefore it's like a privilege
escalation vulnerability where
that's and and people have that
assumption and like maybe even the
person triaging and filing the bugs and
there's again two separate people so
it's already been looked at twice have
that same assumption but the
documentation when you go and look at it
clearly states like that is not that's
not a promise. So those are the type of
things where like oh it the initial
estimation even s it goes the opposite
way too like if we have like a very low
severity. So confusingly we call
severity S0 and S1 and S2 and S3 and we
also have S1 S2 uh S0 within our table
but like for these lower severity S3
within Google we will also go and
sometimes reward much higher like that
also has happened. So, um, yeah, the
initial just know that the initial
triage and how it's filed has nothing to
do with your end reward, unfortunately.
It's usually close, but not always.
>> Yeah. Adding on uh on to the AI thing
specifically, um, in one of your recent
episodes, Justin, y'all mentioned kind
of the concept of manual hacker with
assistance from AI.
>> Super happy with that, right? we we are
totally fine with those types of
reports. Um it's mostly an issue with
having AI writing your reports. And also
I I've heard some feedback, okay, well
maybe English isn't my first language.
I'm using AI to rewrite my report for
me. Feel free to just submit your report
in your native language. whatever you're
more comfortable with, we have Google
Translate
um that we can use internally on your
report and it'll probably communicate it
a little bit better than AI can trying
to interpret your report.
>> Yeah. Wasn't there like some some Gemma?
Yeah. Translate Gemma models that just
got released too by Google. U there's
some new open source models out there.
>> Oh, we have it built into our our our
system actually. So,
>> really?
>> Yeah. So, like to and it's been like
that for a long time. So submit in
whatever language you're uh you feel is
appropriate. Um last and maybe it should
have been first. I know we've talked
about it a lot but I can't reiterate it
enough. If you think we have something
fundamentally wrong, like it's not just
the Justin of the world who have like
personal relationships with Google that
can push back and ask questions and be
like no you're wrong because of XYZ even
if we end up disagreeing which has
happened like ask questions come back
with like rationale like new rationale
of why you believe you this is the
incorrect and it's not uncommon that we
change our reward. So please like you
can reach out through the bug discord
like people like we prefer the bug but
like there's all sorts of avenues to get
more in-depth conversations about your
specific issue and I've had maybe our
top one of our very very top researchers
saying like it's very uncomfortable for
me should I do this and part of the life
hacking event in which we doubled his
award he actually got like $30,000 extra
dollars by like pointing something out
that like it was like a nuanced edge
case that we missed.
um that took it from like S1 to like
unauthenticated and S0 uh which was a
huge step up for like three of his
reports.
>> Wow.
>> So yes, so like feel free like we do
then go back and like evaluate your
arguments um to see like oh did we miss
something?
>> That's great. That's awesome. And and I
can vouch, you know, for certain that
you guys have always had excellent
dialogue um on that. So, I do appreciate
that a lot. Um, any final comments from
y'all on the, you know, free form tips
to hackers on how to improve their
reports? I think that was a good a good
run there for sure.
>> I'm good.
>> Yep. All good.
>> All right, let's move to the actual
scenarios then. I kind of looked at So,
this is this is going to be fun. Um, I
looked at the policy and I was reading
over all of the different um, sections
and and uh, delegations, you know, that
there are there and I was trying to come
up with scenarios where there could be
ambiguity. Um, and so let's see how you
guys handle these uh, uh, in some actual
scenario assessments. Um, so we've got
the ones that I put in the doc, but I've
also got um, you know, another one here
which you mentioned earlier regarding
this xfilling the time of a certain a
certain model became trained at. Um, I
wanted to ask about this because one of
the things that's a little bit tricky
with your um, table here and I'll go
ahead and share my screen as well for
those that are on YouTube is that some
of these are descriptions of the
vulnerabilities and some of these are
impacts
um, is what it seems like to me. So, for
example, project takeoverful
administrative control is an impact from
a vulnerability, not an actual
vulnerability itself. Um whereas you
know down here we uh where is it here?
Um
like which one did I have in my in my um
scenario here? Like global resource name
prediction or collision is is like a a
description of a vulnerability, right?
So what happens if we have a scenario
where global resource name prediction uh
allows you to accomplish full project
takeover? Where does that lie?
Yeah, I'll I'll take this one. Um
probably use a little bit of
clarification in our table on this. So,
generally we will start from the top of
the table and work our way down.
>> So, what that means is
>> if even if your report involves global
resource name predictability
predictability/colision
if the impact of that is full project
takeover, you will get the reward for
full project takeover. Um, and the S2
categories are um kind of used as a a
catch-all for those scenarios that are
not high enough impact to warrant these
higher rewards, but we still want to
reward something, right? So maybe this
is like a temporary DOSs situation would
be a great example.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, that doesn't result in read or
write, right? The attacker may not get
much out of it. It still has impact to
the victim.
I see. Okay. So, if we are achieving the
impact that we're that we're showing,
you know, higher up in the table, then
we should be able to get that that
reward. But then we go back to the
Xville time scenario. Technically, that
is a cross where is it? Uh here
>> it's like S0 it would have been like S0
probably F,
>> right? So, so like an S0F single service
privilege escalation read potentially
cross uh you know cross tenant, right?
Um
so technically we we hit that impact. So
are are we going to you know hit that
table and then get smacked with a bunch
of downgrades? Uh is that how you do it
or would you put in a different category
>> in that case? So like
the typical S0F that you see like we're
typically talking about like meaningful
customer data there. In this case we
decided that it was so like we couldn't
apply enough downgrades honestly
comparatively to the average and you
think about like what is the average
case for like cross tenant read that
seems reasonable. So no we went to
probably like S2 something very very
very minimal. Um, and even then you're
like, again, ask yourself as a
researcher,
how what would the an attacker do with
this information? Why would they want
it?
>> Um, and that helps inform maybe your own
perception of like the impact and where
this would fall.
>> That makes sense. That makes sense.
Yeah, there's nuance to it, you know,
because some of these are are
vulnerability descriptions and some of
these are are impact descriptions, but
at the end of the day for y'all, it's
what can you do with the data as an
attacker, you know, and what is the
actual impact on the system regardless
of what mechanism you you reach but then
but then Darvid Cot we have an
interesting conundrum which is any
excesss on GCP results in rce on all of
the instances that that user has access
to. Right? So
we we we get in a in a in a weird
situation where it's like you know
should we pock for you that we can
convert an XSS into RC on all of the
victims systems or is that assumed or is
that integrated into the the table
>> and typically like you're talking about
C0 at that point
>> uh which is integrated in like that
$20,000 like again like the some of the
things about the client side attack and
where there is more nuance between some
of the client and server side attacks is
like how scalable is the attack
>> and that is something if are you going
to have to individually identify each
specific target
>> um again like and it also depends on
their initial privileges like of what
privileges then you get as the attacker.
So those are why like the big difference
between client and and server side of
like how scalable is it? Is it like
arbitrary victims or is it like very
specific victims? How easy is it to do?
And typically and again nuance but in
like these rare cases where it might
honestly the vulnerability be on the
server
>> but you have to individually target and
send them a link and do other things
makes it more client sideish. That would
be like the way that we reward.
Certainly there's some some difference
between that, right? You know, where
where there's like, you know, we're
compromising Google's infrastructure
versus we're compromising all of the
accounts on a on a you know, a client's,
you know, infrastructure. I'm wondering
if the delivery mechanism is also
considered at all for you guys because
uh like you just mentioned, right?
because surely there's a different
scenario where we we have to like email
the guy that runs your cloud, you know,
for your organization and he's got to
have Google Cloud open in one tab and
then he's got Gmail open in one tab and
then he clicks my link and then you know
and then there's like this whole flow.
Um that's a different scenario than if
we provided I guess let me phrase this
as a question. Is that a different
scenario than if we provided a delivery
mechanism that allows us to very cleanly
and easily exploit somebody with
qualified permissions for the thing
we're trying to accomplish like a
ticketing system within GCP where you
know by nature of the fact that the user
is looking at our ticket they have
access to the resource that we need to
exploit this and and thus have
established a very consistent delivery
mechanism.
Yeah, that those would be rewarded
differently. Um I mean internally we are
looking at the maximum possible impact
regardless of how you frame the
vulnerability, right? So we'll we'll do
our best to find to think of ways that
other ways that this could be exploited
other than how you framed it in your
report. But um as a hacker that latter
scenario is clearly more impactful
clearly. Um, and it's it's worthwhile to
think about those methods of attack that
uh reduce that user interaction.
>> It cuts both ways, hackers, it seems.
You know, that's kind of what I'm trying
to test you guys on here is like, are we
getting, you know, asymmetrical
downgrades on impact versus upgrades,
right? And and what that your answer to
that question showed is that we're also
getting, you know, those upgrades,
right? we can prove full full attack um
you know delivery mechanisms and stuff
like that and and as an attacker what I
would love to see you know as a as a bug
bounty hunter is that also codified in
your policy um you know cuz because we
we have the downgrades um you know
codified in some capacity but
extraordinary delivery mechanism or
something like that could also be an
interesting upgrade to be able to
present to the to the uh hunter. What
are your thoughts on that?
We haven't and again like these were
more recently reworked. I will say since
the table was reworked, we have been
providing upgrades more consistently.
But you're right, it is not like
>> I love that.
>> But like for interesting attacks like I
think we've recently given someone who
was a credit but like it was more of a
bug than a vulnerability like a like I
think it was a thousand or 3,000 I can't
remember which but like upgrades for
unique and novel attacks. So um I think
it would be hard to codify but we do
have additional impact where we again we
think like hey for this attack might be
S1 but like given the product and given
the ease and given these other things we
are willing um to and again people on
the panel advocate for more money for
the researchers.
>> That makes sense. Um the next area that
I wanted to ask you guys was can you
explain the S2D programmatic or scalable
and unauthorized access to non-C
customer data. So this seems to be
relating to like um project ID leaks or
sort of gadgets that you guys might
actually be willing to reward as as
vulnerabilities.
>> Yeah. So this is uh we we actually added
this category in response to kind of a
specific set of vulnerabilities that we
were receiving that we were having a
hard time categorizing. So this kind of
refers to the concept that we were
talking about earlier like maybe you're
getting access to metadata or training
data something. It's not directly
customer data like it's it's not PII
um but it's still something that you
know maybe you should not the attacker
should not be able to access. Um, an
example of this would be like project
IDs. Project IDs, for context, are set
by the user. They can have kind of
company info in there. So, it's it's
sensitive. They're not supposed to be
leaked. Um, and maybe you found a
vulnerability that can leak thousands of
these project IDs from one specific
product. Um, that would be something
that ideally fits into this S2D
category, right? So it it can't fit into
S0 or S1 because it's not really
sensitive enough customer data. Um so
this S2D category is really data driven.
>> And I'll say too like sometimes we
downgrade. So hint for the researcher,
sometimes we downgrade like hey you
don't have the project ID typically like
those are things that like in and of
itself it doesn't give you information
but it can be used for other attacks. So
like keep that in your back pocket like
if you want like you don't necessarily
have to like put it in but when there
was a highp downgrade ID that we didn't
get over but that's for things like
project ID or like UYU ID like attacks
where you're like hey you don't have to
you don't have this you don't like have
this information available you're you're
giving us a specific attack because you
know it because of your other like
project that you spun up. You can say,
well, like there's also this way and
then there's no down, right?
>> That makes a lot of sense. So that
that's cool. This category is if you
want to submit this gadget or whatever,
you can, but also you can use it in
chains and other reports. That's good.
Um, all right y'all, that those were the
questions I had that we have time for
today. Um, thank you guys for coming on
the pod. I I I hack on Google a lot and
I learned a lot about um, you know, how
all of that works. So, appreciate you
guys giving us the tips and tricks. Um,
is there anything that you guys wanted
to shout out uh at the end of the pod
before we close?
>> No, just like we appreciate all the all
the love uh and all of our researchers
uh like the amount we've given out like
3.5ish million this year uh this past
year.
>> Wow.
>> Huge in comparison and uh
>> we love uh everybody reaching out and
thank you for having us on the program.
>> Awesome Derby. Yeah, I I'll echo what
Cotay said and also add on that, you
know, Google Cloud may seem scary to
start with, uh, difficult product sets
for some, but there are a lot of bucks
to be found here. I've said this before.
Um, not a lot of hackers are working on
this attack service, so there's a lot of
opportunity. Don't be afraid to just
submit a report and see what sticks.
We're happy to see you here.
>> Awesome. Thank you guys so much for
coming on to the pod today. Peace.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.